SENIOR MANAGER - INFRASTRUCTURE PROJECTS

Summary

Motivated IT Operations Manager with strong background in Project management, Process improvement and Problem management.

IT Operations experience includes management and leadership in Network Operations Center, Firewall and Security, Windows Servers and Web Intranet, B2B and B2C.

Project Management experience includes successful NOC transition to managed services provider, Network SSL/VPN appliance selection and deployment, Load Balancer infrastructure selection and deployment, Application server replacement and wireless infrastructure installation for remote site, Cisco Telepresence deployment and overall budget management of 3.2 million for 2014.

Extensive Process Improvement using ITIL (V2 and V3 certified) framework for Incident, Change, Release and Problem management. Lead ITIL incident Management assessment, designed and implemented Change Management Board for all of IT, designed and implemented Problem Management process for IT Operations departments.

Problem management experience using Lean Six Sigma (Green Belt certified 2013) focused on application system sales closing process which resulting in \$280k in productivity costs 2012-2014.

Highlights

- Project Life Cycle Management phases and process groups PMBOK framework
- Process and Value Stream mapping Six Sigma
- Control Chart and Process Capability measurement and analysis -Six Sigma
- ITIL Incident, Event, Release and Change management process development and measurement
- Project planning and resource management using MS Project 2007
- Network Operations Center Management KPI and SLA development and measurement
- Service manager experience with outsourced managed service providers

Accomplishments

2013 - Achieved Lean Six Sigma Green Belt Certification

2012 - Awarded ABInBev top Talent award for managed services transition

2010 - Implemented IT Enterprise level Change Control Board - process established as Excellence Program best practice for all ABInBev IT.

Experience

Senior Manager - Infrastructure Projects

January 2014 to Current ABInBev Corporation i1/4 City, STATE

- Successfully (on budget, schedule and scope) managed program level project for Data Center Viability which included Network, Middleware, Storage and Power (UPS) streams. Budget management 1.8 million.
- Successfully (on budget, schedule and scope) managed program level project for Workplace Viability which included workstation, laptop, printer refresh for US and Canada zone locations. Budget management 1.4 million.
- Took on project management for rolllout of Telepresence in US and Canada (28 systems). Collaborated with Global IT team and British Telecom provider.
- Lead PMO team in the development of Flight Plan (project life cycle process groups) for Infrastructure projects. It iwill be implemented as

Senior Manager - Network and Security Operations

January 2011 to January 2014 ABinBev Corporation i1/4 City, STATE

- Managed the 24X7 Infrastructure Operations Center which provides 2nd and 3rd tier incident and problem management for windows server and data network platforms.
- Lead incident resolution and root cause analysis utilizing PRTG Netflow data and Netscout packet flow data.
- Managed the firewall security team in daily perimeter security checks Firewall Denies; Outbound proxy access and B2B business partner
 access.
- Performed project Transition Manager role to transition 2nd tier network monitoring and incident management team to outsources managed services model.

IT Manager I - Network Operations

January 2008 to January 2011 Anheuser-Busch Companies - ABInBev Corporation il/4 City, STATE

- Managed a fifteen member team consisting of outsourced 2nd tier incident management technicians and employee based 3rd tier technical problem management resources for network and server incident resolution.
- Directed activities and personnel of the IOC technical support department which operated 24X7 and performs proactive and reactive monitoring and incident management for the corporation's global network and server infrastructure.
- Senior management liason for major and Sev1 Incidents.
- This role requires leading and managing cross functional teams for multiple technologies (SWAT teams) to resolve issues.

IT Manager II - MS Server Operations Support Manager

January 2007 to January 2008 Anheuser-Busch Companies il/4 City, STATE

- Manager of the Windows Server Support team, scope included 1800+ production servers, monthly patching, remote business unit support
 including the migration of Canada Labatt server infrastructure.
- Leader and Core team member of ITIL process improvement effort focused on centralizing incident management for It Operations.
- ITIL process improvement effort lead to the formation of the Infrastructure Operations Center (Network and Server). As a result of my leadership in the effort I was selected to manage the new department.

MIS Manager-Web Operations

January 2002 to January 2007 Anheuser-Busch Companies il/4 City, STATE

- Beginning as the MIS Team Leader for Release and Incident Management in 2002, optimized incident and release management processes
 using ITIL framework.
- Scope of work included B2B Extranet Environment.
- Promoted In 2004 to Sr.MIS Team Leader and expanded management and role to also include enterprise Intranet Environment.
- Promoted in 2006 to MIS Manager with expanded management that included the enterprise B2C Internet brand (Budweiser, et al) sites.
- Defined, developed and implemented Problem Management process for Web Operations.
- Managed the Problem Management Team which was comprised of a rotating staff of 3rd tier technical design and architecture resources.

MIS Business Analyst - ENA System Administrator

January 2000 to January 2002 Anheuser-Busch Companies il 4 City , STATE

- Developed Release Management Process for 23 application migration from a private dial-up mainframe based B2B information exchange system to an Internet based web technology enabled B2B environment.
- Developed process for formal user acceptance testing of applications and incremental roll-out (740+ wholesaler business partners) of web based applications which reduced incidents and disruption to the core business activities.

Technical Consultant Sr. Technical Analyst Technical Support Analyst

January 1996 to January 2000 Programming Management System Incorporated $i\!\!\!/\!\!\!4$ City , STATE

Contracted Consultant to Anheuser-Busch

Team Leader for Sales Support Hotline

Team leader for BudNET Wholesaler Hotline

Test Engineer for BudNET Wholesaler Applications

Manager Inventory Systems

January 1982 to January 1996 Angelica Uniform Company i $\frac{1}{4}$ City , STATE

Multiple positions - progressed and promoted from entry level clerk position to management level and responsibilities.

- Production Control Clerk
- Manufacturing Systems Administrator
- Payroll Manager
- End User Support Specialist
- Inventory Management Systems Manager

Education

M.~A: Information Technology Management , 5 2010 Webster University i\/4 City , State GPA: GPA: 3.97 Inducted into International Honor Society for Business Administration - Delta Mu Delta - Lambda Kappa Chapter

Information Technology Management GPA: 3.97

Inducted into International Honor Society for Business Administration - Delta Mu Delta - Lambda Kappa Chapter

B.S: Computer Science Math and Computer Science, 5 2008 Webster University i1/4 City, State, USA GPA: 4.0

Computer Science Math and Computer Science GPA: 4.0

Credentials

•ITIL V2 Foundations – Certification 2004

•ITIL V3 Service Support - Certification 2008

•ITIL Practitioner Release and Control - Certification 2008